So the legend goes VLC can open
everything. What's the weirdest thing
that you know that it can open? You know
that there is a ton of people who are
using VLC to record VHS videos, right?
Like it's just like you plug it with a
capture card and you can basically
record VHS video. Well, how does that
work? Basically, it's you know those
type of capture card where you can put a
peritel in
or VGA and you put that and actually VLC
can play those type of card and there is
a module which allows to control
directly some those VCR camcorders.
We support DVD audios lately, right? We
spent the the summer working on DVD
audio support. And like there is no no
one's making any DVD audio support.
There is a custom encryption schemes.
What about Lucas Film?
>> Oh, yeah. And there is of course all the
weird codecs support game codecs
supported by by FFmpeg. The one Star
Wars video game, the first 10-second
opening sequence, someone has gone and
implemented that and make sure that's
bit exact on one disk that existed at
one time of one little sequence in the
game. And then funnily there was a at
one VideoLAN conference we made a
competition to meet make the weirdest
and most horrible file ever and see if
VLC could play it. What did it end up
being? What's the file? It was an MKV
file made by Derek which each of the
frame was changing resolution, aspect
ratio, rotation and then and it was like
Did it work? Yes.
And there was another one where
the whole video was actually animated
subtitles, right? SSA, right? So
this one was and so each each frame was
a black frame, but on top of that there
was a a subtitle that was animated for
each frame. There was a file that's a
valid zip and a valid MP3 at the same
time or something like that, so So yeah,
we made a competition of stupid files.
And it worked. It opened all of the
stupid files. Yes.
>> By the way,
uh for people who are not familiar, I am
wearing a hat. Would it be fair to say
this is the best worst logo of all time,
the cone?
Yeah, by far, right? The logo of VLC is
so iconic, right? Like we are a team
with a small number of people and and
the icon is known everywhere. I go to
middle of nowhere in India or in China,
people know the cone, right? And and 25%
of the website traffic that comes to our
main website is cone player, right? So
so many people don't know VLC, right?
They know the cone player. That's the
thing they Google for, it's cone player.
Yeah, they go on Google and they they
put cone player and and they download
VLC, right? So that's iconic. And once
we tried to change it as a joke, right?
We said it was going to be a a type of
caterpillar
construction and we said that during
April 1st
we had around 10,000 emails saying no,
don't change the logo and so on, right?
So it's so iconic, right? It's so
distinctive, right? If you want to do a
video player, you're going to put a play
button on a TV, right? And that's a
YouTube YouTube logo, right? It's an
original. This one is orange, right?
Very bright and and it's weird. And it's
ridiculous and it's absurd and it's
hilarious. It becomes meme and meme
becomes culture. And you keep it and you
know about it and you know that in 20
years like you still have going to have
the cones and remember oh yeah, that was
a video player. Yeah, and we'll talk
about, you know, the the mission of
FFmpeg being a kind of the archival
aspect of it. So you could think about
1,000 years from now we'll have all
these videos that only VLC can open.
Humans human civilization has already
destroyed itself multiple times and the
only thing that will remain is this like
you know, the the cockroaches will be
crawling around and it'll be the VLC
logo with our some of the archival
footage that VLC can open and the aliens
will show up and they'll press play and
they'll get to see
>> Well, we really really hope so, right?
But there is also so many memes where
people say, well, I'm sure I can put a
pancake inside my DVD drive and VLC will
play it.
No, we tried it, doesn't.
But we actually have a video of us
trying that. Didn't work. A codec for
physical reality, I don't know what that
would even look like.
>> guy who did that, right? He he he he
printed a small cone, right? Like the
the ones we we distribute as goodies and
inside he put an RFID chip
which was his way of playing a movie,
right? And so he put this on RFID player
and when he put that it was playing like
the last Star Wars and so on. So instead
of having like DVD boxes, he had like
VLC cones all around and he plugged that
and there was like physical objects.